I'm your host, Henry Arcelinian, and welcome to this other episode of the Future of Money
podcast, where really we go discuss with some of the taught leaders in the space and really
try to actually bring you some actual color on what's happening on a practical perspective,
including the crypto markets, but also the crypto industry more generally.
And today we're joined by Nick Philpott, Nick, who's the co-founder of Zodiac Markets.
Nick, great to have you on the show today.
Thanks for having me, Henry.
You know, fun fact guys, for everybody listening, Nick started his career actually.
Obviously, he's the co-founder of Zodiac Markets, and we'll talk all about that in a second,
but he started his career in finance in Nigeria, which I find is very interesting.
We'll talk about emerging markets, including Africa and Nigeria in a second.
But the part that I love the most is that he studied at St. Andrews University,
and he worked as a bartender in St. Andrews, where apparently used to serve even Prince William
back in a day.
So is that true?
Yeah, that's true, that's true.
And Kay Middleton, or the Princess of Wales, as we should call her now.
Yeah, gin and tonics, Bombay Sapphire and Tonic, if I remember correctly.
My God, here we go.
You have the insights on their favorite drinks.
You can't go wrong with that.
Well, Nick, great to have you on the show.
I have to say, I've had the people, I always like to ask a fun fact about people
when they come on the show, because I think it creates this human bond with us.
It's the first time I hear something, a story as well, is what you just mentioned,
as a bartender for the royal family.
But here we go.
That's what it makes.
Also, crypto is so interesting as well.
Well, Nick, before we jump right in, there's a couple of topics I want to discuss today.
But can you give to our audience a bit of background on yourself,
but also on what is Zodiac Markets, and what do you guys do?
And also a particular question.
How is different from Zodiac Custody?
Yeah, yeah, it makes sense.
Nick Philpott, when I started in finance after leaving the British Army,
I worked for a bank called Standard Chartered Bank.
Many people will be familiar with them because they sponsor Liverpool Football Club,
so that's where everyone will think, "I remember that name, but not from where."
So I worked for them for 16 years, as you say, started in Standard Chartered Bank, Nigeria,
covering local financial institutions of banks and embassies and charities, that sort of thing.
I moved back to London, and then just had a career across financial markets.
So that's sort of the trading part of the business, the trading floor.
And that culminated with me working in the electronic trading division.
It was the head of market structure.
And actually, another fun fact, amongst other things, we worked with Libra,
or DM, for two years, so the Facebook stablecoin.
I want to talk about that for sure.
Yeah, yeah, no problem.
And then in terms of Zodiac Markets, so we started working on it about 2020.
We followed on from another company that you mentioned, Zodiac Custody,
our sister company.
And really, what they do, Zodiac Custody, as the name implies,
provides safekeeping of digital assets.
Zodiac Markets helps you execute those digital assets into other things,
or other digital assets, once you bought them.
We work with other custodians, they work with other brokerages and exchanges,
because really, it should be all about giving clients the choice that they want.
The last thing I'll just add on that, what we wanted to do as a bank was to emphasize the
segregation of the activities of custody and execution.
We think it's much better having that separate.
But isn't it ironic, Nick, and I want to talk more about what you guys do in a second.
But when you look at traditional finance, a lot of the banks,
let's look at a prime brokerage, for example, they have execution and custody together.
Actually, they're able to offer portfolio margin in cross-port, and optimization,
if you want from that perspective.
Whereas in crypto, it's actually the exact opposite approach you guys have taken,
where separating markets and custody, what is that?
And you think this will change over the coming years?
Well, I mean, if you go into a big bank, then actually those activities are segregated.
But they're in the same legal entity, they tend to be in the same building,
but you have information, walls, and all those sorts of things.
As you rightly implied, the really dangerous things to combine are market making and the
activity of custody, because then the phrase that people use is the temptation is to put
your hands in the client's cookie jar, so to speak.
The best example is FTX, and it's great to see that that's ended so well,
potentially, knock on wood, for a lot of the asset holders finishing up in the money,
as it were.
But we felt that having seen the way the lot of crypto asset firms were doing it,
we were needed to really emphasize that segregation, that your assets are off-balance
sheet, both from your custodian and from the entity that you're choosing to execute with,
and they are safe.
The nice thing with crypto assets is we start to use not only digital asset technology,
but things like APIs and so on and so forth.
So for example, we could have a look through to clients' assets in that custodian.
A lot of people in the industry are now calling that off-exchange settlement.
We can lock those assets and then mirror them back onto our platform.
So that way, if we were to go under, heaven forbid,
then assets are exactly where they started and they're to be handled back to the client.
And so how do you guys compete?
So for example, there's numerous execution desks in crypto.
I mean, forget it even tried to fight, but all crypto alone.
You have numerous OTC desks, execution desks.
I mean, the market is quite competitive right now.
How do you guys want you guys pitch?
How do you guys are different?
Of course, there's a standard charter link, but how do you guys pitch yourself as having a
differentiator compared to all the other desks on the market?
Yeah.
So in setting the parentage and the counterparty risk and the good
structuring and all those sorts of things aside, the biggest USP is that access to banking.
Yeah.
It is certainly still not right that a lot of digital asset firms struggle to access banking
and even customers who want to start using digital assets are worried about being
de-banked by their existing providers because they're engaging in crypto asset activities and so on and so forth.
Because we're owned by majority owned by standard charted bank,
that gives us the privilege of being able to open bank accounts, not only in dollars,
but also in a whole range of other currencies and in particular those currencies of those
countries where crypto is actually as active, if not more active than say the United States or Canada
or the United Kingdom or the European Union and so forth.
So examples would be places like Kenya, the United Arab Emirates, Singapore, the Philippines and so on and so forth.
What we can then do is we can then combine that with the foreign exchange capabilities of the bank.
So a lot of those crypto asset natives as I was mentioning, if they're struggling to get access
to banking, imagine what the quality of the foreign exchanges that they're getting access to.
And we've come across some pretty startling, startling situations.
I mean, one of our most valued clients now, they were paying 400 basis points of 4%
for dollar dirhams to their previous bank provider.
Which, and those are the kind of rates you expect to see in a regional airport, I mean really,
really, really egregious. So we're able to come in and basically take foreign exchange liquidity
and combine that with stablecoin liquidity in particular to provide our clients with faster
and cheaper execution. So the last point I'll just add is that because we can then integrate
very deeply into the bank's ecosystem, that allows us to move the fiat even more quickly.
As anyone who's running digital asset execution business will tell you, fiat is always the problem.
It's too slow, it's too unpredictable, it's too expensive. Working with our parents and getting
that to speed up, we're able in many cases to get the fiat to land T0 in some cases in minutes.
So for example, we're very lucky and this is public knowledge that standard charted banks circle,
the issuer of USDC and Eurocoin. That gives us almost the unique capability to mint and burn
USDC in under five minutes, 24/7. And the first time we ever did the test of that was on a Saturday
morning and my word, it was satisfying to see it land four minutes, 52 seconds after settlement.
Interesting, but I mean, I see your point where the fiat, the on-ramp and on-ramp that you have,
actually, as an entity, Zonia markets has obviously is different here because other OTCs,
they have to go and try to get these different banking rails, which obviously is a competitive
advantage you have. But I would argue that it's still the problem because let's say you're moving to
crypto to fiat, when you're wiring this to somebody else as a client's bank account,
it's still going to be stuck in the system, right? And I guess the alternative here, what would be
optimal is that standard charter starts opening up accounts for crypto clients because then somebody
could be a real client and then it can literally on a T0 basis, even literally move the assets to
the client's bank account. But to the best of my knowledge, standard charter is not opening accounts
for crypto companies, at least at scale, right? Not at scale. No, it has to trade a very fine
line between the regulatory pressures that it finds itself under and the scrutiny and rightly so.
And it obviously has commercial obligations as well to its shareholders and it's got to make sure
that it's opening accounts in its own interest, it's got to make sure that it generates the right
return on its time and resources invested. So it is public knowledge that it does already bank
some counterparties, Coinbase, for example, so there's articles on that. So that does help us.
But critically also, what helps us is when we're speaking to corporates, so large multinationals,
and they are either mass consumer goods companies or brand companies who are starting to use NFTs
or oil and gas companies who are starting to buy stablecoins from us in order to
transact in oil cargoes, cross border, that's the beauty. We're able to book transfer the
fiat currencies from our bank account to their bank account or vice versa. And those settlements
three to five minutes, again, it's very, very quick. As long as they're a client of the bank
in their normal operations, yeah. That's correct. That's correct. But even after that,
there are other ways that you can try to speed up fiat. So for example, you can make sure you're
integrated with separate rails in euro, you can make sure that you have onshore banking. So at the
moment, a lot of our banking is offshore out of the UK and Singapore. So the next stages for us are
to deepen our integration with those payment systems. So in UAE and Turkey, we're working with
partners of standard chartered to get banked by them so that we can deliver fiat much that much
more quickly. And I think you're right, because I think this could be a comparative advantage,
because especially the use of stablecoins in emerging markets, and I want to talk about this
in a second, especially your experience with Libra, but I think the market, the mass market,
including media and everybody underestimates how much stablecoins are being used in emerging
markets, and in cross-border payments. I wish there was some more accurate data,
but what's happening between Latem and Africa, or Africa and Asia, using Tether or USDC and other
stablecoin, FDUSD and others. I find it very, very interesting that that's one fact that is
not provided. I think I can see now for you guys when at the Zodiac markets, if a client, I'm an
oil trading firm, and I have an account with standard charter, and my clients actually often,
many of them don't want to admit it publicly, but they prefer using stablecoins for their settlements,
to make it so difficult to get a bank account, this can give you a really, really good comparative
advantage out of that perspective, including the FX side as well. No, absolutely. And it's
just about knocking down those counter-arguments that a lot of people present when you're trying
to pitch using digital assets to them. And then just also just to answer the unasked question,
what standard chartered is kind of perception on this? I mean, standard chartered recognises
this is going to cannibalise some existing businesses, but that's kind of a natural evolution.
But it's the bank recognising that it's already on the menu, and along with many other banks,
but it has the choice, along with many other banks, but they're not making that choice,
to be on the seating plan as well. So by running companies like us, by running companies like
Zodiac custody, and indeed it's planning to offer its own custody solution, powered by Zodiac custody,
out of DIFC, then again it can give that reassurance to counter-party thinking, there's a lot of career
risk in making this first step, but actually it looks a lot better for I'm using something that's
backed by a large multinational bank that either we bank with, or we certainly know from its 170
year history. Absolutely. If I was running sales at Zodiac, that's exactly the people that you're
pitching to, they don't want to get fired, they tend to be quite conservative, somebody in treasury,
there's a lot of these recognisations, they've been there for 10, 15 years, they put their own
careers before that of the company, and in this case you guys are a good bet of a safe hair pair
of hands that there's somebody to blame, you know, which is good on that side. I would even argue
ironically there's a big advantage here where for even standard chartered not to get new crypto
clients, but actually bank go to its existing clients and say, hey, we have Zodiac markets,
we have Zodiac custody, we have this competitor advantage, and let's try to take advantage of that.
And what's your goal on the emerging market side? I mean, we mentioned at the introduction,
Nick, how you started working in Nigeria, what is the, let's say from the client base you guys
were seeing, and when you're mentioning your differentiator, it could be this emerging markets
element, what kind of activity are you seeing, where people are using on off-ramps or stablecoins
in the broader emerging markets, and how do you think this is going to evolve over the coming years?
Yeah, I mean, I could probably drop most of our clients into three categories at the moment.
So the first of the crypto natives who, as I said, you know, they're just struggling to get
access to decent foreign exchange, so they're using that just in their normal course of business.
So large flows we have, you know, Turkish liras, Emirati dirams, Bahraini denars,
singer-dollars, things like that. So that's just sort of a day-to-day business.
The second, and also actually I should just layer on there, they also value the reliability
and having a counterparty that has reliable banking. I think after, you know, September 23, a lot of
people, including us, have seen some of their counterparty suddenly turn around ago, got a problem,
I can't settle dollars anymore, or, you know, insert currency here. And we're seeing some clients
getting de-banged. So second group though, to move on, our payments companies, so doing cross-border
payments, so that could be either retail cross-border payments or wholesale cross-border payments,
or indeed remittances, so people, say, moving money from the United States to Mexico or from the
UK to the Philippines, and so on and so forth. And there it's a real emphasis on speed and cost.
It's not necessarily having to beat the cost, but just be the same as the existing providers,
because it's the implicit costs that we can really target. You know, a remittance company,
for example, in order to give the illusion of an instant payout, it's just having to run very
large balances in local currencies in the destination countries. And that's obviously bleeding
effects volatility, inflation, and so on and so forth. The third group, as I touched upon,
sort of primary commodities, I mean, it started with oil and gas. And that's really a reflection
of the fact that stablecoins, I don't think, are going to disrupt, you know, the major payment
channels, New York to London, Singapore to Hong Kong. It is going to disrupt channels, you know,
like Latin to Africa, Southeast Asia to the Middle East, and so on and so forth.
Places where getting, for example, dollar banking is a real challenge. And if you do manage to get
dollar banking, then the quality of that dollar banking is either very, very unreliable, because
that local bank has to go through so many correspondence that it's taking, I mean,
let alone two days, it's taking five days. And again, in a high interest rate environment,
you've got capital that's just tied up, you're not getting interest. So even though the stablecoins
don't pay yield, no one really cares to borrow the old, you know, moniker, you don't have to
outrun the bear, you just have to outrun the other guy. And the other guy has correspondent banking.
Yeah, which is, I mean, it's a no brainer on that front. I agree with you. I think these big
quarters will not be disrupted, but a smaller ones. And there's a lot of those small colored
corridors, right? There's a big opportunity. Let's talk about stablecoins. You know, when I was
hearing you speak right now, Nick, I was thinking, okay, if you go to your, you know, 1000 biggest
clients in the bank, right, I would go to them and say, guys, you have an account with standard
charter. Why don't you put an account with your markets or custody? And we're able to actually
give you some benefit. You have a competitor advantage over the rest of you save all these
correspondent banking fees and so on and so forth. And obviously, because you're using stablecoins
behind the scenes, USCC tether, I'm wondering when I was listening to you, why don't you guys
launch your own stablecoin? Because then you really control every vertical of the value chain. And
you get to keep the interest rate as well, instead of paying it off to, or to circle or to tether.
It's a very good question. And it's one I've been asked multiple times. I mean, from our
perspective, it's, we've got a lot on our plates, just with the business model that we've got.
And as you can imagine, it's sort of battle, but it's a lot of work to get a company like Zodiac
markets or Zodiac custody through a large bank, through their regulators, you know, in a satisfactory
way. And rightly so, there's a lot of due diligence, a lot of risk management, doing things the right
way. That takes time. I reflect that now that there are already 25 currencies that we're aware of,
that have stablecoins linked to them. So I actually think that the easier opportunity is where many
of those issuers have already done kind of that first, you know, learning process with the regulators,
or they have links with their local regulator. So they've kind of got that local comfort. They've
managed to sort of get the first steps, build the tech, so you can do the minting and burning.
I think the bank's real opportunity is to come in and start banking the stablecoin issuers,
because then we can repeat the trick, figuratively speaking, that we have with USDC, and we're looking
to repeat with a few others where we can do that minting and burning 24/7. And there are still
opportunities for the bank. It can be a deposit provider to the reserve. It could be a broker for
treasuries or for the repo, again, for the reserve. It gets payments for the issuance and the redemption.
Then we're doing the sort of the distribution, if you like. And then if there's FX hedging,
so if someone's buying USDC, but they're buying it with Turkish data, we're doing a dollar Turkish
hedge with a bank. And then once you've got your stablecoin, so do your custody, you can custody
them. So I think I've counted off seven. There's a slide somewhere I've written for the banks to
what I call seven revenues of stables. And I think it's a great opportunity.
On a percent, I agree with you. I think for a lot of these big organizations,
like Senator Charter, have a presence in many parts of the world that are involved in corporate
banking, even forgetting, often in crypto, in the early days, and I was partly responsible,
that I would say, like we used to often think, I used to even think myself that the big opportunity
was in wealth management, where you can go off for these crypto products, maybe the opportunity
was when retail banking offered your retail customer access to Bitcoin or other products.
But the more I think about it, especially in the current environment where we're seeing
with the problems, I forget even bank account opening with U.S. correspondent banking,
but I would even argue that the whole digitalization that is going on or that conversations
around the digitalization around the world, I'm actually surprised some of the competitors to
standard charter, namely HSBC. Somebody spent 15 years of my life in Hong Kong. We always like to
bitch against HSBC, but I find it very interesting that the bank has not been involved in this,
for example, more actively, exactly replicating what you guys have done, for example. And
to a certain extent, I would argue the big American counterpart as well,
City or GPM, you can argue they've done some initiatives, especially on the GPM side,
but I think it's a very interesting opportunity you bring forward, Nick. I can see how you guys
have a USB on that side. Yeah, I think so. It puzzles me slightly with the other banks,
the same as you. A lot of the banks, when they're looking at digital assets,
they're looking at tokenizing securities or tokenizing carbon credits or some other kind of
financial instrument. So there's regulatory overhead, there's then an open door to create
the excuse of we need to rate for regulatory clarity. So that's going to take multiple years
and so on and so forth. The problem you have, from my opinion, is the elephant in the room is cash.
So once you actually start running a digital asset business, you realize that fear is always
the problem in your operational settlements. It's too slow, too unpredictable and too expensive.
So for example, if you tokenize a carbon credit, then fantastic. We could do a trade today, we could
move the carbon credit from me to you, but the money that you pay me is not going to arrive until
Monday. So you fundamentally, you're back where you started. So focus on cash and yes, people could
go, well, central bank digital currencies are coming along. Yes, I think they've got a place,
potentially, but they're going to be definitely national. I don't see them being as suitable for
cross-border payments. Yes, for example, I could use the EUN here in the UK, but in Bista Village
and Harrods, that's not really universal acceptance or adoption. Whereas stablecoins, I think, because
they're sitting on internet rails have the ability to move across. The last bit I'll layer on is I
feel like we're just getting started, particularly on the cross-border trade side. So to illustrate,
if you're buying an oil cargo with stablecoins, the next logical thing is to tokenize the bill of
lading that represents the cargo on the ship. A law was written last September to allow that
under English law, the Electronic Trade Documents Act. As far as I can tell, I'm no trade expert,
but it's an unregulated instrument. So very straightforward. Now it's on the same chain as
your means of payment, and you can move them synchronously, or you can put them both into escrow.
And I think it's just starting with those basics, rather than, for example, targeting financing.
Just focus on the assets that are moving around, then work out how to do the money.
I mean, there's a whole layer of smart contracts you can put in there. There's a lot of stuff that
come in and make a big difference. It's funny you mentioned bill of lading. When I was a young
law student, and one of my masters agrees, my thesis was about letter credits and bill of laddings
in international trade. And at the time, this is almost 20 years ago, I was shocked how the
industry had not evolved in 100 years. And now 20 years later, I mean, more shocked how it's not
not changed at all. That's what industry is still using faxes, and it's completely
inefficiently. And many people have tried, but I think what you're mentioning is very interesting.
I want to touch up on stablecoins more particular, I mean, and CBDCs. I mean, let me start with CBDCs,
because you just mentioned you do not believe CBDCs will be used on a cross-border basis.
And I appreciate your example with the ECNY. But what you think, do you really think the market
will prefer a US dollar stablecoin issued by a private company versus a potential CBDC issued
by a country or central bank that could not be the US, but potentially something else over that?
I think unless the central bank has the courage to place that stablecoin or that CBDC, whatever you
want to call it, on a permissionless ledger on the open internet, it's not going to get the same
benefits or provide the same benefits of the open internet, either to it or to the potential users.
And I just don't see any central banks really having the courage to take that step and to shame.
In terms of the sort of the private sector side of things, yeah, I think what we'll see
is we see different design approaches. And certainly, for example, we see USDC. That's already got
a huge amount of adoption. People like it because it's already got a degree of recognition. But
then you have PayPal coming along, so that's a huge brand recognition. Then you've got Paxos,
still US regulated. They've just released a yield token. So that's another slight sort of variation
on the theme. And then you've got Tether, which many people look upon as a euro dollar because
it's not issued by a US entity. So I think having that sort of let a thousand flowers bloom, so to
speak, I think would be very, very interesting. Yeah, absolutely. I totally agree with you. I think
the stablecoin ecosystem is not very sexy. People don't look at it, but it's extremely profitable,
and it plays as such an outsides role. And what I find interesting as well, when I meet people in
emerging markets, often the first interaction with crypto is by stablecoins. They mentioned Turkey,
Nigeria, I mean, pretty much Africa, Latin America. I've done myself so many transactions
we pull around the world on stablecoins from South Africa to even America, just because it's so
it's so much more convenient. What I want to ask you is, you know, I've done in my last book,
the book of crypto, I have, I don't know, I think 20 pages on Libra and it's whole from Libra 1.0
to 2.0 and 3.0. And then the collapse, if you want, or collapse, or let's say the cancellation of it,
you guys were involved in that Libra adventure. We will share with our audience on the Libra
expansion. And more particularly, why do you think it did not work as well? Now that we're a
couple of years behind. Yeah, okay. So, so beyond the statutes limitations or something like that,
although I'll keep the end, the NDAs, I'm sure still apply in some way. So I'll be careful. But
joking aside, so finally enough, it's how I met Max, who co-founded Zodia Custody, our sister
company. So he and I literally met in front of Facebook in 2019, back in February. So that was
before the white paper. I think they would have done it if they started with the team that they
finished with. I think they sort of went around perhaps had the wrong attitude unknowingly or
unwittingly with some of the regulators that they met. And they're just the wrong messages went out.
I think the evolution from the original multi-currency single coin to multiple single currency coins
was very positive. That was where we really started paying attention. Because then if you've got,
I think there's five different currencies on the same chain, then the opportunity to do payment
versus payment settlement. So that's where one leg moves at the same time as the other leg and
contingent on the other leg. That removes counterparty settlement risk. At the moment, the way that
financial, financial markets manage that risk is using CLS. Very, very expensive, only works T plus
one or T plus two. And for pairs like dollar versus Singapore dollars, it only works four hours a day
Monday to Friday, give or take. It's just not good enough operating hours for global financial
infrastructure. Yeah. So I think it's interesting, you mentioned a bit of the cowboy attitude at
the start. It's like move fast, break things, works in tech. It doesn't work easily in banking as well.
But do you think there was an element also of geopolitics in the sense that if you and I lost
more stablecoins, it's not going to really threaten the US dollar as a reserve currency. But if a
company with over 2 billion monthly active users launches a currency in a way, don't you think that
this was actually kind of there was a real threat to the status quo system? I think that probably was
whether that was understood or not is another matter. I think just people felt instinctively
uneasy and don't get me wrong. Facebook has had its issues with data privacy and the Cambridge
Analytica and certain things like that. But the way that I saw it was that this was potentially
the first major opportunity to undo the cause of the root cause of those sort of privacy issues,
which was the original sin of the internet, as Mark Andreessen calls it. So back in 1994,
the internet was really starting to get going. Netscape and Mark Andreessen and Microsoft were
working with some of the big payments companies. And they'd realized there was just going to be
no way they could get payments into the browser. So as a result, the sort of economic model of the
internet became based on advertising. And if you're advertising, you need to know, are you male,
are you female, are you fat, are you thin, so on and so forth, you need all of that personal
information. Instead, if you can get to a point where you're monitoring the wallet and you're looking
at what that wallet is using, it's what that wallet is spending on, then you can advertise
to the wallet rather than individual. So the need to capture all of that personal data actually
starts to go away and you can unwind that original sin. Ironically, I was at an event
earlier this week, and I saw a remittance company who've integrated with WhatsApp,
and I'm sitting there thinking, it's funny, I remember seeing the exact same thing in 2020.
That's really what, you know, where we should get to, you know, being able to send money,
like a text message, like an email, I think is going to do more for global poverty than
many things that many people have done in the recent part. Absolutely.
And I think I would argue that, I mean, I talk about my book, but I think the motto that Libra did
at the early days was that in a world that you can send an email for free, WhatsApp message,
SMS, pretty much for free, instantaneously anywhere in the world, why sending money is so
complicated. It's actually unacceptable, frankly. It's a great story. One day, I think you'll tell
your kids, your grandchildren, all the little stories behind Libra that took place, you know.
Completely. Well, one thing I would add is it also helped us just as a bank,
because if you're going to internal compliance teams or risk teams or people who just know nothing
about crypto and you're trying to explain it, you're going, right, Bitcoin consumes lots of
electricity. There's this guy that no one knows who it is, Satoshi Nakamoto. There's lots of
volatility. People just go, no, not interested to get it. Whereas if you start with the conversation,
you go, it's pegged to the dollar, the reserves are about bony melon and Facebook's doing the tech.
Everyone goes, okay, all right, we'll give you a hearing and we'll, let's find out what this is
all about. So it's a good way for us as an organization to learn. Absolutely. I think it takes out
the career risk as well from that perspective in regards, right? Well, I think we're going to go
through quickly in a minute left that we're going to go through a far round of questions. I'm going
to ask you quick questions. I need to one or two word answers and hope you're ready. Hit me.
Perfect. So Nick, what do you do when you're not working? What's your favorite thing to do when
you're not off work? Cycling. Interesting. What do you cycle in the UAE? Al Wathba, so big 30
kilometer track in the middle of the desert with street lighting. It's amazing. Beautiful thing.
I was going to ask you my next question. What's your favorite thing to do in the UAE and you live
in Abu Dhabi now? Yeah, so okay, if not Wathba, then just swimming. You know, beautiful seas,
beautiful beaches. Great way to relax. What industry would you be if you're not in crypto?
The Army. The Army. Yeah. My next question actually, if you could join any military unit,
Army, Air Force, Navy of any country, which one would you want to join? The Royal Gurka Rifles,
which was the regiment I was due to join. I got medically discharged from Santos. That was career
plan A. You know, never mind. I'm very lucky even in spite of that. You joined the battle,
the crypto industry, another way. Yes, exactly. You studied the history and university at St.
Andrews. What part of history do you find the most interesting? Business history. So it's not
well studied, not well understood, and it's what makes the world go round. Absolutely.
The history of money. I think it's one of the most interesting topics ever.
If you could go back to university today, you studied history. What topic would you study
knowing what you know now? I would study Samson Gideon, who was the Rothschilds of the 18th century.
He financed the Seven Years' War. One day, I would love to do a PhD on that.
Amazing. Amazing. If tomorrow you're the CEO of a big commercial bank, what's the one thing
you would do regarding crypto that you wish a lot of CEOs would be doing right now?
Change the risk appetite so that you are happy to provide basic banking services.
Exactly. Very, very interesting. What surprises you the most about the crypto industry?
The collaborative nature of it. It doesn't feel adversarial.
Yeah, it's absolutely correct. It's one of the few industries, especially in the last year.
And so if people are in it, they're going to be in it for a long, long time.
Yeah. And again, to wrap it up, again, Nick Philpott, co-founder of Zodiac Markets.
This is Nick, the traditional question. Anybody comes on my show.
Nick, if you could have lunch or dinner with one person dead or alive, lunch or dinner with
one person dead or alive, who would you have lunch with? Robin Williams. Easy.
Wow, Robin, why is that? Interesting. I don't think I'd eat anything. I'd spend the entire time laughing.
Missed out far. It must be one of the best movies ever. I haven't ever had this answer.
I've asked this question for many years all the time. I love it. Nick, where can people
learn more about you or more about Zodiac Markets? Well, LinkedIn, so www.zodiacmarkets.com.
We've got lots of sort of financial history stuff there on the website if you fancy looking at that.
Otherwise, hopefully, more part with this podcast and more to come.
Awesome. Well, guys, thank you very much. Hope this was a useful episode, guys.
Make sure to also check out my YouTube page. We have a lot of content there as well.
And it was a big thank you for all the support for the podcast.
This podcast now is at the top 5% of all podcasts globally on Spotify.
So, guys, really big thank you from the bottom of my heart. I really,
really appreciate the support of each one of you.
Thank you very much, guys, and see you all soon for another episode of your future money podcast.